<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hacking on Cas van Cooten</title><link>https://casvancooten.com/tags/hacking/</link><description>Recent content in Hacking on Cas van Cooten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://casvancooten.com/tags/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>So You Wanna Hack a Bank? 'Global Central Bank' (PACES) Certification Review</title><link>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2021/10/so-you-wanna-hack-a-bank-global-central-bank-paces-certification-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2021/10/so-you-wanna-hack-a-bank-global-central-bank-paces-certification-review/</guid><description>Introduction The &amp;ldquo;Global Central Bank&amp;rdquo; (GCB) labs and accompanying &amp;ldquo;PentesterAcademy Certified Enterprise Security Specialist&amp;rdquo; (PACES) certification are definitely something else. It is more or less the &amp;ldquo;level-up&amp;rdquo; from the respective &amp;ldquo;Attacking and Defending Active Directory&amp;rdquo; (CRTP) and &amp;ldquo;Windows Red Team Lab&amp;rdquo; (CRTE) courses, also provided by PentesterAcademy. GCB is the hardest of the three, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for more beginner-friendly material, you&amp;rsquo;re probably better off reading my blog post on CRTP instead.</description></item><item><title>Building a C2 Implant in Nim - Considerations and Lessons Learned</title><link>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2021/08/building-a-c2-implant-in-nim-considerations-and-lessons-learned/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2021/08/building-a-c2-implant-in-nim-considerations-and-lessons-learned/</guid><description>Nim for offensive security For a while now I have been playing with the programming language Nim in the context of Offensive Security. Nim is a relatively young and fairly unknown programming language that has a syntax quite similar to Python&amp;rsquo;s, so is very easy to pick up. It however offers the flexibility and low-level capabilities of languages like C/C++, and has a great foreign function interface. On top of that, it compiles to native C (as well as some other languages), which results in native binaries that are quite slim.</description></item><item><title>Operate Like You Mean It: 'Red Team Ops' (CRTO) Course Review</title><link>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2021/07/operate-like-you-mean-it-red-team-ops-crto-course-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2021/07/operate-like-you-mean-it-red-team-ops-crto-course-review/</guid><description>Introduction If you hang around the infosec &amp;ldquo;twittersphere&amp;rdquo; or in other security communities, odds are you have already seen someone share their experiences on the &amp;lsquo;Red Team Ops&amp;rsquo; course by ZeroPointSecurity. I had heard a lot about this course prior to enrolling in it myself - almost exclusively consisting of positive reviews. The author of the course, RastaMouse, is quite a well-known figure in the infosec community. You may know him for his open-source tool contributions, such as Watson or ThreatCheck, or if you are a HackTheBox-enthusiast you may know him for the RastaLabs pro lab.</description></item><item><title>Getting the OSEP Certification: 'Evasion Techniques and Breaching Defenses' (PEN-300) Course Review</title><link>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2021/03/getting-the-osep-certification-evasion-techniques-and-breaching-defenses-pen-300-course-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2021/03/getting-the-osep-certification-evasion-techniques-and-breaching-defenses-pen-300-course-review/</guid><description>Introduction When Offensive Security announced the new PEN-300 course, also called &amp;ldquo;Evasion Techniques and Breaching Defenses&amp;rdquo;, the syllabus immediately intrigued me. The course promises to provide an advanced course, aimed at &amp;ldquo;OSCP-level penetration testers who want to develop their skills against hardened systems&amp;rdquo;, and discusses more advanced penetration testing topics such as antivirus evasion, process injection and migration, bypassing application whitelisting and network filters, Windows/Linux post-exploitation and lateral movement (hello Active Directory!</description></item><item><title>Windows &amp; Active Directory Exploitation Cheat Sheet and Command Reference</title><link>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2020/11/windows-active-directory-exploitation-cheat-sheet-and-command-reference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2020/11/windows-active-directory-exploitation-cheat-sheet-and-command-reference/</guid><description>Last update: November 3rd, 2021
Updated November 3rd, 2021: Included several fixes and actualized some techniques. Changes made to the Defender evasion, RBCD, Domain Enumeration, Rubeus, and Mimikatz sections. Fixed some whoopsies as well 🙃.
Updated June 5th, 2021: I have made some more changes to this post based on (among others) techniques discussed in ZeroPointSecurity&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Red Team Ops&amp;rsquo; course (for the CRTO certification). I&amp;rsquo;ve re-written and improved many sections. New sections have been added on DPAPI and GPO abuse.</description></item><item><title>Getting the CRTP Certification: 'Attacking and Defending Active Directory' Course Review</title><link>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2020/10/getting-the-crtp-certification-attacking-and-defending-active-directory-course-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2020/10/getting-the-crtp-certification-attacking-and-defending-active-directory-course-review/</guid><description>Introduction As a red teamer -or as a hacker in general- you&amp;rsquo;re guaranteed to run into Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Active Directory sooner or later. Almost every major organization uses Active Directory (which we will mostly refer to as &amp;lsquo;AD&amp;rsquo;) to manage authentication and authorization of servers and workstations in their environment. It is a complex product, and managing it securely becomes increasingly difficult at scale.
It is exactly for this reason that AD is so interesting from an offensive perspective.</description></item><item><title>Try Harder: Yet Another Journey To OSCP</title><link>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2020/05/try-harder-yet-another-journey-to-oscp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2020/05/try-harder-yet-another-journey-to-oscp/</guid><description>The first part of this blog post dives into my personal OSCP story. If you&amp;rsquo;re only interested in stuff you can apply to your own PWK journey, jump to the key takeaways or the OSCP FAQ.
Preamble I don&amp;rsquo;t have a very technical background. I did a Master&amp;rsquo;s in Information Science before starting as a Cyber Security Consultant. In my current role, I deal with various cyber topics on an organizational level - usually not from a very technical perspective.</description></item><item><title>OSCP Cheat Sheet and Command Reference</title><link>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2020/05/oscp-cheat-sheet-and-command-reference/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casvancooten.com/posts/2020/05/oscp-cheat-sheet-and-command-reference/</guid><description>Updated May 18th, 2020
Since my OSCP certification exam is coming up, I decided to do a writeup of the commands and techniques I have most frequently used in the PWK labs and in similar machines. I aimed for it to be a basic command reference, but in writing it it has grown out to be a bit more than that!
That being said - it is far from an exhaustive list.</description></item></channel></rss>